about just how accurate are the memories that we know are true, that we believe in? There is decades of research, examples and examples of cases like this, where individuals really, really believe. None of those teenagers who identified him thought that they were picking the wrong person. None of them thought they couldn't see the person's face. We all have to be very careful. All our memories are reconstructed memories. They are the product of what we originally experienced and everything that's happened afterwards. They're dynamic. They're malleable. They're volatile, and as a result, we all need to remember to be cautious, that the accuracy of our memories is not measured in how vivid they are nor how certain you are that they're correct. Thank you. (Applause)
en ce qui concerne la justesse de nos souvenirs que nous savons être justes, que nous croyons. Il existe des décennies de recherche, une multitude d'exemples d'affaires comme celle-ci, où les individus croient vraiment. Aucun des adolescents qui l'avaient identifié, ne pensait qu'il désignait la mauvaise personne. Aucun ne pensait qu'il n'avait pas pu voir le visage de la personne. Nous devons tous faire très attention. Tous nos souvenirs sont reconstruits. Ils sont le produit de ce que nous avons vécu initialement et de tout ce qui c'est passé après. Ils sont dynamiques. Ils sont malléables. Ils sont volatiles, et en conséquence, nous devons tous nous rappeler d'être prudents, et que la réalité de nos souvenirs ne se mesure pas à leur vivacité ni au degré de certitude de leur exactitude. Merci. (Applaudissements)